<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on</title><link>https://alcaemre.com/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://alcaemre.com/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>COG499 Research Log</title><link>https://alcaemre.com/notes/COG499/COG499-reading-list-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alcaemre.com/notes/COG499/COG499-reading-list-notes/</guid><description>Erik Hoel Quantifying Causal emergence Shows that Macro Can Beat Micro (2013) Can Micro Beat Macro? Integrated Information Across Spatiotemporal scales (2016) Agent Above, Atom Below (2017) When the Map Is Better Than the territory (2017) What Caused What?</description></item><item><title>levin-reading-notes</title><link>https://alcaemre.com/notes/levin-reading-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alcaemre.com/notes/levin-reading-notes/</guid><description>The Biophysics of Regenerative Repair Suggests New Perspectives on Biological Causation (M. Levin, 2020) Anatomical “macrostates” can be implemented by a wide range of molecular and cellular arrangements and even time-series trajectories that all implement the same large-scale outcomes.</description></item><item><title>PHL340 exam prep</title><link>https://alcaemre.com/notes/PHL340-exam-prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alcaemre.com/notes/PHL340-exam-prep/</guid><description>PHY331 7 Q 6 points each formula sheet multiple parts
biased towards second half of course
psets first lectures next then computationals wink wink nudge nudge chemical rate plots PHL340 to study treat study exam like a take home test think critically about the content, like where to object Artificial Intelligence and the Mind What are the main theories of consciousness we encountered in the course?</description></item><item><title>PHY342 functionalism paper planning</title><link>https://alcaemre.com/notes/PHY342-functionalism-paper-planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alcaemre.com/notes/PHY342-functionalism-paper-planning/</guid><description>quotes What is functionalism? &amp;ldquo;Functionalism is the philosophy of mind based on the distinction that computer science draws between a system&amp;rsquo;s hardware, or physical composition, and its software, or program.</description></item><item><title>PHY460 definitions</title><link>https://alcaemre.com/notes/PHY460-definitions-and-important-theorems/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alcaemre.com/notes/PHY460-definitions-and-important-theorems/</guid><description>1-Dimensional definitions and Theorems Generalization/reduction of order reduction to a system of first-order differential equations $$\frac{d}{dt} \vec{x} = \vec{f}(\vec{x})$$ enables plotting in phase space usually depends on a substitution of $y = \dot{x}$ and solving for y Existence &amp;amp; Uniqueness $\dot{x} = v(x)$ has a unique solution around an initial condition $(t_0, x_0)$ provided the functions are smooth in the service of the Lipschitz condition Lipschitz Condition $[L]$ $\forall x, y \in (a, b), |v(x) - v(y)| &amp;lt; k |x-y|$ this implies that $v(x)$ is continuous and a finite derivative exists almost anywhere $$ \frac{|v(x)-v(y)|}{|x-y|}&amp;lt;k, \ k\text{ being a finite number} $$ this effectively means that solutions reach a fixed point in finite time Bifurcation quantitative change in behaviour creation or destruction of fixed points change in stability of fixed points Saddle-node bifurcation has the normal form $\dot{x} = r + x^2$ when $r&amp;gt;0$, no fixed points when $r=0$, 1 fixed point (semi-stable) when $r &amp;lt; 0$, 2 fixed points (1 stable, 1 unstable) fixed points appear and disappear Transcritical Bifurcation normal form: $\dot{x} = rx-x^2$ one fixed point is maintained, but undergoes a change in stability.</description></item><item><title>PHY460 definitions</title><link>https://alcaemre.com/notes/PHY460-definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alcaemre.com/notes/PHY460-definitions/</guid><description>Overview The importance of being nonlinear phase space the space where the axes are the parameters of a system of differential equations we are interested in drawing trajectories when given a system trajectory a curve drawn by the solutions (say $(x_1, x_2)$) to system (say $(\dot{x}_1, \dot{x}_2)$) in phase space.</description></item><item><title>TAME</title><link>https://alcaemre.com/notes/COG499/TAME/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alcaemre.com/notes/COG499/TAME/</guid><description>Technological Approach to Mind Everywhere: An Experimentally-Grounded Framework for Understanding Diverse Bodies and Minds Michael Levin (2022)
link to paper</description></item><item><title>Tattoo Documentation for Jess</title><link>https://alcaemre.com/notes/jc-tattoo-inspo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://alcaemre.com/notes/jc-tattoo-inspo/</guid><description>Placement I&amp;rsquo;m thinking on my right arm or right leg. I&amp;rsquo;d be very interested in pieces that work well with motion, preferably spanning two joints.</description></item></channel></rss>